So here, we have a slightly more complex program.
在这里 我们有一个稍微复杂的程序
This program declares a vector of strings called brothers.
此程序声明了一个称为兄弟的字符串的向量
This is my brothers David, Ethan, and Adam.
这是我的兄弟大卫伊森和亚当
Then we iterate over this vector and output the name of each of the brothers.
然后我们迭代这个向量 输出每个兄弟的名字
If we run this,
如果我们这样
let me make sure I'm in the right directory, g++ hello.cpp./a.out.
让我确保我在正确的目录 g++ hello.cpp./a.out
So we say hello to David, Ethan, and Adam.
所以我们跟大卫 伊森和亚当打个招呼
What I would like to do now is try and debug this program,
我现在想做的是尝试调试这个程序
just to inspect what's going on on each line.
来检查每一条线路上发生的情况
So you might think I could come up here and start debugging, but in fact,
所以你可能觉得我可以上来开始调试
Visual Studio Code is only set up out of the box to debug
Visual Studio 代码仅设置在框外进行调试
Node.js which is not helpful for us as C++ developers.
作为 C++ 开发者  Node.js 对我们没有帮助
So I'm going to come to the extensions directory and search for
所以我要到扩展目录搜索
C++ and I see the Microsoft C++ extension which is what I want to install.
C++ 和我看到了 Microsoft C++ 扩展 这是我想要安装的
So now I've installed that.
现在我已经安装好了
I'm going to come back to hello.cpp and I'm going to try and debug again.
我将返回 hello.cpp  我将再次尝试调试
Now I'm able to debug C++.
现在我可以调试 C++
When I start debugging I get nothing.
当我开始调试时 我一无所获
Let's try coming to the debug option here and select my environment.
让我们来尝试这里的调试选项 选择我的环境
Nothing happens.
什么都没发生
Here in the bottom right corner I see an error.
在右下角我看到一个错误
Please first open a folder to do advanced debug configuration.
请首先打开文件夹以执行高级调试配置
So I'm going to actually have to put hello.cpp in its own folder.
所以我要把 hello.cpp 放在自己的文件夹里
So let's open a folder.
让我们打开一个文件夹
I'm going to create a new folder within my temp directory called Hello.
我要在我的临时目录中创建一个名为 Hello的新文件夹
Then I'm going to click okay.
那我就去点击好了
Now I have this blank folder called Hello.
现在我有一个空白文件夹叫做 Hello.
I'm going to move
我要搬家了
my hello.cpp file which was in the temp directory into this temp Hello directory.
位于 temp 目录中的 temp 目录中的 hello.cpp 文件
So now I see I have hello.cpp all over again.
现在我看到我又有个 hello.cpp 了
Let's try just compiling it and running it here to make sure everything still works.
让我们试着整理一下 在这里运行 以确保一切仍然有效
All right. Now let's try debugging it.
好吧好吧 现在让我们尝试调试它
Let's say we want to stop at this breakpoint.
让我们说 我们想在这个断点停止
That's how we set a breakpoint,
这就是我们设置断点的方式
is we put this red dot here.
我们把这个红点放在这里
Next to the editor on the line that we want to stop the debugger at,
在编辑器旁边 我们要停止调试器
we're going to say start debugging.
我们会说开始调试
Now I get this option for all the different types of debugging configurations.
现在 我为所有不同类型的调试配置获取此选项
I'm going to choose g++ build and debug active file.
我将选择 g++ 构建和调试活动文件
Actually I'm going to come over here and add a configuration here,
实际上我要在这里加一个配置
g++ build and debug active file.
g++ 构建和调试活动文件
So let's say I want to debug a.out.
所以说我想调试 a.out
Let's create
创建
a launch configuration.
启动配置
Let's delete this and now let's debug.
让我们删除这个 现在让我们调试
Let's see. Now we have to load our symbols.
让我们看看 现在我们要加载我们的符号
So it's not enough to just compile the file and build a.out.
因此 仅仅编译文件和构建 a.out 是不够的
We need to compile the file with the debug symbols.
我们需要使用调试符号来编译文件
So we'll say hello.-g and we will run on that.
那我们就打个招呼
Now you see we stop at
现在你看到我们在
standard cout hello brother and we can look at the status of the program.
标准的 cout hello brother  我们可以查看程序的状态
We have these strings that are my brothers,
我们有这些兄弟
the active brother is David.
活弟就是大卫
If we continue to the next breakpoint,
如果我们继续下一个断点
we see the active brother becomes Ethan.
我们看到活哥变成伊森了
We can just step through the code to add them.
我们可以通过代码来添加它们
Now we're done. That's an example of how to debug a program.
现在我们完成了 这是一个如何调试程序的示例